edinburgh.gov.uk 2016-11-26

# Privacy Notice | Privacy | The City of Edinburgh Council

## Privacy Notice

This Privacy Notice explains how we collect and use the information about our customers so that the services you request can be delivered effectively and efficiently. When you use our website we collect and analyse data so that we could improve our services. 

The Data Protection Act and other legislation regulate how we use personal information you provide.  Personal information includes details such as your name and address, your bank details and any information about your circumstances that are necessary for the Council to deliver services to you.

### Sharing your information with other organisations

We will provide information about you to organisations such as the Department of Work and Pensions and other regulatory organisations if the services we provide to you need us to do this. 

We may also pass information about you to the police or other crime detection agencies if the personal information requested meets the criteria set out in the Data Protection Act 1998 or other legislation.

To help us provide you a high quality of service to you we may also ask your consent to share personal information with organisations such as NHS Lothian or agencies from the voluntary and charity sectors.  If you do not give your consent we will not pass personal information to these organisations unless there is a statutory duty to do so or if there is a duty of care placed on the Council to disclose information.

### Data matching

We are required to ensure that we protect the money available for the provision of Council services. We will use the personal information about you to help us to do this. Data matching involves cross checking the personal information you provide to various Council service departments for accuracy.  

Examples of this are the payment of benefits and application for school enrolment.

We are required to provide personal information about service users to Audit Scotland for data matching purposes to assist in scrutiny of the provision of public services and for the prevention and detection of fraud.

### Using data for research

Sometimes we use data held by the Council to carry out research which help us evaluate and inform how we deliver services.  You cannot be personally identified from any published research we produce from it.

### Your information rights

You have the right to make a request to get a copy of the personal information that we hold about you.  You can also ask us to correct  your personal information if it is incorrect. You can contact us for details about how to do this. 

**0131 200 2340  **

Read further information about Subject Access Requests. 

### Visitors to our website

You could use our website as a registered user or you could stay anonymous. If you don’t register and sign in your personal details are not recorded unless you choose to submit an online form.  If you choose to register and sign in you will be able to access a wide range of services online.

### Website and Digital Analytics

We and external companies we employ on our behalf use digital analytics for monitoring website performance, usage and improvement as well as displaying and targeting advertising elsewhere on the internet.

This information is collected and your personal information is removed so you cannot be identified. For further explanation read our Cookies policy.

### Use of cookies

Read further information on use of cookies.

### Links to other websites

This Privacy Notice only covers the City of Edinburgh Council website. We do not give any guarantees about the accuracy of the content or the security of any other website that you may access through a link on our website.  If you visit other websites you should read their Privacy Notice covering the use of personal information.
